this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at sc-radio.net
the radio is brought to you by the IEEE
computer Society software Magazine
online at computer.org software
hi everyone I'm Priyanka raghwan for
software engineering radio today I'm
going to be chatting with Neil Waltman
who is the co-founder and CEO at arnica
me is an experienced information and
application security leader and he's
been at a bunch of companies I just want
to call out he was a VP at security at
finastra and also see so at cabbage
apart from that he is given talks at
many different conferences including
black hat Defcon b-sides and RSA and
today we're going to be chatting about a
concept called pipeline less security so
welcome to the show near we're very
really really happy to have you on board
thanks Priyanka it's really my pleasure
to join okay is there anything else in
your bio that you would like listeners
to know about you before we jump into
the show I I think that put aside the
title or maybe my my history I really
have that State of Mind of a hacker I
like to develop code maybe just to prove
a point but not necessarily to develop a
production product for that I have my my
co-founders to help with that but I
really like to code I really I'm really
obsessed about developer experience and
how developers actually perceive
security because at the end of the day
if you want to help developers to get to
a specific point whether it's in
security or quality you really need to
understand them first together yeah I
think that's really great and wonderful
to hear because I think one of the
things for people who are building
products for developers and their
experience it's almost like a servant
Leadership Model right because you
really need to serve the people who you
know use your product so let's get on to
the show and before we start looking at
pipelineless security could you explain
to our listeners what is a pipeline okay
so think about a pipeline as an
automated script that is stupid quickly
being kicked off when certain event
occurs in your source code management
system so for example it can be when you
maybe open up a pull request in that
case you might just want maybe just
build that container that you're going
to deploy or maybe it can be also an
event that occurs when you merge a pull
request or we make changes to a pull
request and in that case let's say that
you merge the pull request what is
typical to see is certain tests are
being executed so for example you have a
script that builds your software another
script that maybe runs certain
integration tests within your
environment that you're trying to deploy
and eventually also runs that deployment
script so that piece of the pipeline is
essentially automated based on events
and you have multiple systems that have
a predefined configurations and scripts
that you can actually
scale that process in a fairly simple
way great and I guess today the problem
is are there any problems that you see
with the ability to integrate security
into your pipelines so I think that
there are some challenges when it comes
to integrating security into pipelines
first of all you actually need to work
with the either devops or sensor of
Excellence or even developers to
actually modify the scripts within your
pipeline to embed your security tests in
it and let's say that you do have the
buy-in either for management or the
developers like you even then it's very
siled so think about companies that have
you don't need to go far with thousands
of thousands of thousands of repos think
about a company with 100 of repos how do
you go and deploy your security tools
where it actually matters and you get
that 100 coverage where it matters to
the business that is the challenge
because you need to go and work with
multiple teams and modify the scripts to
meet their scripting standards not only
that what happens if let's say tomorrow
a new team spends up a new repo maybe
they want to develop a new microservice
how do you ensure that you're going to
be there as well so you always need to
chase someone to embed your security
tools into that pipeline to add to that
sometimes people because the task of
getting onboarding people onto the
pipelines is so huge that they think
that's security they're done they've got
the pipeline so I've done my security so
that's another challenge I guess right
yes and and it also depends what you're
actually doing with that because at the
end of the day one of the trends that we
see is that many companies utilize even
open source tools and embed them into
pipelines and then it becomes more of a
I would say maybe feature creep but
essentially a an essential vulnerability
management challenge that you might have
of for example how do you exclude
vulnerabilities that are maybe not
applicable maybe false positives how do
you manage all of that in a centralized
way which is quite challenging with open
source and this is also the reason why
you see many commercial products running
open source to provide you that wrapper
to actually manage all of those
vulnerabilities in a central place okay
and before again we move into pipeline
list another question I need to ask you
is what are the three kind of top risks
that you see in your research on repos
three security top risks yeah so one of
the risks that we see is not necessarily
an evil risk but it's something that
just occurs one of the things that we
tested quite widely with our hypothesis
initially and eventually ended up seeing
that a bit more in the wild is where
access to code equals access to Cloud
let me just explain what it actually
means today there's an increasing trend
of something that is called inner
sourcing inner sourcing is a process
that is very similar to how let's say
Google or Amazon work where you have
right access to all repos you can
contribute to every repo in the company
but for you to actually deploy that code
it needs to go through a pull request so
you can essentially create your own
feature Branch you can develop the
feature you can create a pull request
and then only after it's being it's
approved only then it goes and
deployment what we see is that there are
quite a lot of and quite a lot is not
quantifiable but I would say that we see
almost 50 percent of the repos that are
misconfigured in a way and by saying in
a way it can be either don't have any
enforced pull request process so for
example if you think about like a GitHub
for example they have a code donors
functionality right so you have a
specific individuals that their approval
is counted towards the ability to merge
because everyone can approve but then
whose approval counts in other cases we
see misconfigured code donors files so
sometimes you do configure that but it's
not working so for example you do have
maybe a configuration file maybe a
setting in your let's say in Azure
devops for example just a setting on the
branch protection policies and even then
it's optional and it's not enforced when
you have that optional setting and not
enforced setting this is where access to
code means access to Cloud obviously
there are some caveats whether you can
approve your own pull requests or not
but that's the gist of it so that's
essentially one thing that we see with
repos the other thing that we that we do
see is that it's kinda Associated to
that is also unenforced status checks
that are important for the organizations
so for example if you have have a status
check to validate maybe your software
composition analysis issues or maybe you
have a status check to identify whatever
linkers that you want to run it can be a
security issue it can be a quality issue
but essentially when you do run texts in
some cases I agree you don't need to
enforce them maybe some of them are good
for like in for your information
purposes only but when it comes to
security tools that's what you do want
to enforce it so for example one of the
things that we see that is quite widely
utilized within our customer base is
something that we call zero new high
severity vulnerabilities policy which
means that whatever I have in a backlog
I will let everyone handle that in their
own pace as part of my vulnerability
Management program but I want to enforce
that all of the changes that were
introduced in that particular feature
Branch will be mitigated prior to the
merge of that code because the problem
space is that security teams Chase
Developers they have the vulnerabilities
they open the gear tickets they need to
follow up with them get the commitments
and when you go and actually you fix
that but in that case because developers
are already in that context of
developing within that feature Branch
it's very easy to say either hey I fixed
it and I focused only maybe on the high
severity and above instead of seeing all
of the risks I focused on on all of that
or I just had a magic wand to dismiss it
but at the end of the day you got to the
point that you have a clean so-called
report that you can actually go and
merge with that and that's where we see
an additional misconfiguration with
those branch protection policies and I'd
say that maybe the last one that we see
that is and that really depends whether
you're a regulated company or less
regulated company we also see quite have
utilization on misconfigured permissions
into the code repos themselves we see
some of that with maybe multi people
admins on repos but in many cases we can
also see just excessive even right
access the main thing is that you can
reduce permissions to minimize the blast
radius when credentials are being
compromised we've seen that with for
example think about like LastPass when a
developer left and could clone the repos
maybe find secrets in there but you
could actually get to the point where
you minimize the impact not only on the
read which is very hard to do if you do
inner sourcing but if you're doing
resourcing you can at least minimize the
impact on the right two resources or to
repos and that's the balance that needs
to be taken I wouldn't say it fits
everyone's needs but these are key three
trends that we see okay great so I so
you're going to be providing us the
magic wand to get rid of this is is that
what pipelineless security is well I
wouldn't say that it will fix everything
because obviously there are some places
where I think that pipelines actually do
way better job than than pipeline less
but at the end of the day maybe maybe
worth going through the three different
places where you can integrate the
security tools and then we can talk
about the pros and cons in each one of
those and that will likely maybe
emphasize where each one of them can fit
okay so what are the three places then
so the three places where you can
integrate security tools are either in
the on the developer workstation you can
put it either as a let's say an IDE
plugin like in your Visual Studio Plugin
or you can put it something that looks
like a maybe a pre-commit hook something
that kind of blocks you or maybe informs
rather blocks depends how you look at
that when you actually commit a code
another place would be in the pipeline
itself in that piece of the script
there's a step in it and the last one
would be pipeline less which is some
some sort of a combination between the
two and maybe we'll go through each one
of them and give these specific examples
so maybe on the IDE you can get maybe a
linter to your source code maybe you can
scan for hard-coded secrets in your
source code maybe you can scan for
software composition analysis issues
such as which third-party packages
you're bringing or maybe low reputation
packages that you want to bring into the
environment but then there are two
challenges that you have with that type
of a deployment one it's extremely hard
to take your security controls and
actually deploy them across let's say a
hundred percent of the laptops owned by
engineering not only that keep in mind
that in many cases developers work with
the different types of Ides so one can
work with Visual Studio code another one
with the clips different versions
different settings workspace settings
and such so it's challenging by itself
but it's it's great because it's really
on the left another challenge with the
same setup is that many tools that run
locally don't necessarily have the
server side context that the Enterprise
wants to enforce so for example let's
say that I did a software composition
analysis scan maybe I looked for a
third-party vulnerabilities in my
packages you will get a list of all of
the vulnerabilities and vulnerable
packages that you have low risk medium
risk High critical and such okay what is
important how does the developer know
what will actually break the merge later
on so there's additional context that
you need to inject for that to be
effective because the moment that you
integrate a tool that scans source code
on the left side you get the challenge
of overwhelming developers and plus it
will scan everything what about the
changes that I made versus everything I
care about the changes that I made at
this point because I'm developing in my
feature branch and not everything so
there's that balance that needs to be
made on the workstation if you look on
the other side on the pipeline you have
very similar challenge with the coverage
to make sure that you're going to have
the security tools embedded in all of
the pipelines and if the new repo pops
up as I mentioned you want to make sure
that you have it there but also what we
noticed in some of the companies that
were integrated with is that when they
utilized maybe more Legacy scanners they
actually ran the scanners after the
build process and sometimes the build
process doesn't take modern times like
minutes sometimes the build process can
take two days so why you run a scanner
after two days and then fail it the only
conclusion out of this is that security
makes you look bad right it's not the
right way to do that another challenge
that we see with pipelines is that at
the end of the day when you do run a
pipeline I mean you see the name of the
person that introduced that break the
break of the chair the break of the
pipeline and such and that is more of a
psychological issue because now you
blame the developer maybe blaming maybe
shaming but it's essentially I see my
name next to a red icon I don't like
that okay now let's go to pipeliners
before that I needed to ask you because
you you really got my goat by that two
days build process is that because it's
a monolith it can be a monolith or it
can be just a bill that maybe comes from
multiple repos or multiple sources or it
can be just a legacy product that it has
so much code even a service can have
very heavy functionality think about a
single service that runs fraud
prevention well for a single service
that is quite heavy or to build
so that's the complexities that you
might end up with okay yeah so that's
something that I think you've clearly
laid out the problem so what are the
choices that we have I think you just to
recap I think you talked about you have
a choice of putting it in the IDE or you
can have a pre-commit book or you can
put it on the pipelines and we've seen
the various problems here in these
different areas because I think it's
always like a trade-off in the balance
and so yeah now if you come into
pipeline lists what are the solutions we
can have so pipelandless is an approach
you can do pipeline less security as
well as you can do pipeline less quality
pipeline Nets is just the concept of how
you should execute the tools the
pipeline left security approach that
we're taking is essentially all event
based so what we see as more beneficial
with pipelandless approach is that we're
actually listening to not only pull
request events but also code push events
so think about the developers that as
they push code while they work on their
code they kind of save their changes
when they push code right that's where
we provide them the feedback and the the
beautiful thing about pipeland list is
that you can apply a lot of logic
Associated to that particular change
because if you look only at those
changes of the code one you can run very
specific scanners to identify specific
risks so for example if you look at
software composition analysis this is
easy if you look at statical analysis
again it's fairly easy to run that but
if you look at maybe Dynamic testing you
can't really do that before you have a
maybe a built or deployed artifact right
which is where pipeline less works it
works with code something that you can
scan rather than a live environment now
when you set that up and you scan all
those code changes so think about me as
a developer I just wrote a piece of code
that maybe has a hard-coded secret in it
if it has a hard-coded secret in it and
you already managed to push that code
regardless which controls you have in a
system now you want to route that
message first to the developer and ask
hey maybe is it a real thing or maybe
you can say to the developer I know it's
a real thing you put me AWS credentials
with root access like it's an it's a big
No-No right so you can have that balance
but you can send the message directly to
the developer and also because it's not
associated to any pipelines you can make
changes in the code itself so you can
either maybe overwrite the secret or
maybe create another Branch for the
developers and do other things there but
at the end of the day because it's not
associated to that particular event you
can actually go make the changes maybe
scrub the secret and send the developer
a direct message and that's place our
implementation via slack or teams say
hey Priyanka we just detected that you
pushed a secret we fixed it for you
click here maybe to merge the changes
into your own personal or your own
feature Branch for example so that's one
example another example would be let's
say that you just pushed a code with a
new SQL injection whatever in that case
because uh we ran the scan maybe
statical analysis on that we identified
that you have a SQL injection in it
again we'll send a message directly to
you say hey Priyanka we did identify a
new risk that you introduced in that
code push this is SQL injection this is
how you fix it and then you as a
developer you are empowered to either
say I'm on it yeah good catch thank you
I'll fix it or you can say you know what
dismiss and dismiss because no there's
no way to control whatever parameter
that comes into there this is indeed a
statical analysis issue but it cannot be
exploited and therefore you may either
dismiss the item or maybe suggest a
dismissal and that will go to an absec
team to approve that you're you're good
with that the whole premise here is that
you pushed code it's real time you got
the feedback you got the opportunity to
respond on that before you open a pull
request now when you go to the pull
request then you can run again the same
scan but this time anything that you
fixed or dismissed will no longer appear
as a failed status check because you
either resolved it or you got the
approval or you dismissed it and now you
have all the green lights to go and you
either review the pull requests or even
merge the code so that's how it becomes
a blameless and Shameless process in
which all of the feedback Works in a
private message to the developer until
everything is everything that is
important for the business is resolved
and again it's not all issues it's only
things that you introduced and maybe
you'll Focus only on the high and
critical severity issues first and then
you'll start blocking others and that
gets you to very minimal work before you
can actually pass the security gates
this is very interesting so I'm just
picturing this it's interesting that you
said that you'll send a message by a
slack just giving an example now what
about all these things with you know we
did an episode on the GitHub co-pilot as
being an AI powered party so do you see
that that's also a future like almost I
mean I guess that's as you type but
would that be again a place where say
this concept could be used as well that
or is that it's a too time consuming
because you have to write the code and
immediately has to run the check I think
it's complimenting because at the end of
the day developers use co-pilot to help
them to write the code but it's not
necessarily going to write the entire
code that they need or maybe when you
add a package well that's a package you
just need that package right so there's
more areas that are not covered by
GitHub copilot that are covered by
GitHub copilot I can tell you we are
users of GitHub co-pilot in the company
we really like it but at the end of the
day it saves up to 20 of the developers
work which is phenomenal but not
necessarily develops the secure code
that we're looking for or maybe when we
want to add external functionality or
embed third-party packages it's not
necessarily the piece that will get all
of that functionality into the code yeah
and also I think when I'm talking with
you I think it also might be a little
bit too intrusive and not very
performant maybe to run a kind of
background check as you write so I'd
rather wait for it to be a part of a
pull request and then do it or yeah part
of my feature branch and then at that
point when I'm ready to push exactly it
can be part of that feature it can be
per push so you can get results for that
push and then push another code and
you'll get new results only for the new
push because you probably don't want to
get all results for the feature Branch
every time it's it creates a lot of
fatigue yeah so this is super
interesting and so let's just go into
the next session where I can dive a
little bit deeper into the this area so
what exactly do you need to actually
implement this concept of pipelineless
Securities this Hook is it it's going to
be a web hook that's listening to every
push event how does it work yes
technically it is you subscribe to
webhooks that will send you any code
posts or any pull requests or any
changes to a full request and when you
get those events then you need to make
that determination based on whatever has
changed there that this is the piece
that you want to scan because maybe it's
a code push you might not want to scan
the entire repo you just look at that
push you look at the data you scan the
data if you need to enrich it you enrich
it with other sources maybe you do need
to make a decision that you do need to
clone the entire repo and do some
additional scans on top of it but it's
it's up to the business logic that you
develop and eventually it's up to that
service that receives the web hook to
take additional decisions such as how do
you know for example if you look at
GitHub right how do you know that the
email of the personal GitHub account
that just pushed code in your slack that
is associated to the corporate like it
may not be on your profile right so
there's a lot of additional logic that
you might need to to write to have that
context but let's say maybe you are
you're willing to do that work manually
maybe you're just willing to go through
each one of the GitHub usernames and map
them to the email maybe have other ways
to do that then it's fine you can route
the message to slack but then you have
other complexities like hey I routed the
message to slack I want it to be
actionable how do you actually collect
it from the developer and put that in
the same process of the decision making
when you open a full request so there's
a lot of complexities in how you do that
but at the end of the day you just want
to maybe ping the developers only when
it's absolutely necessary already that's
the differentiator between different
ways that you can Implement pipeline
that's security okay there's one thing
that we talked a lot about which is the
amount of code coverage right so in
terms of the pipeline based approach or
what we are we're not entirely sure of
the code coverage so with pipeline lens
since you're dealing with small chunks
do you think that the code coverage can
be almost 100 so first of all you do
have a 100 code coverage in your scans
because you can do partial scans or you
can do full scans with a pipelines
approach the things that you need to be
wary of is that there are some timelines
or deadlines to those times that you can
run a pipeline in a pipelines approach
so for example let's say that you post
code and it took me more than I don't
know two minutes to scan it I mean you
probably saved it maybe you already
closed your laptop and you're out of
context so the user experience might not
be that good or maybe if it took me 40
minutes to provide you results every
time it won't get it because maybe you
have a status check you said the status
check is a pending State while you scan
the pull request and then it turns out
not because your process timed out but
because of maybe a GitHub implementation
of how long you can actually be an in
progress or in process State and
therefore when we do our testing when we
look at how fast we scan you know we
test against repos and the size of Linux
so that's like a clone that we have on
our different source code management
tools when we push code then we check
how long it takes to run all of the
scanners that we're looking at and time
it usually less than five minutes think
about the Clone time the Clone time is
included it's a very long long time okay
okay so the thing is so how many checks
do you also run like can that be also
something that you can configure so one
of the things that now a lot of teams
done is they also run like the static
code analysis then they run the static
application secure quality testing and
they do the third party code analysis
and then sometimes there are some people
who are very ambitious they also run a
unit test right they're also doing that
on every pull request and then by the
time they're like they're tired or they
say okay let's check out the security
but that you know it typically happens
right they'll be like okay this thing is
taking too long so what happens with now
what I'm worried about is when you
actually do this you're listening to
this push event can that be configured
on what checks you want to run it's
absolute an implementation in our case
in arnica we do run all if needed so we
do the secret scanning we do static
testing fast run software composition
analysis reputation checks on packages
as well as infrastructure race code all
of that is something that we deliver but
then the time frame that I mentioned
however at the same time sometimes you
can have just simple unit tests and
sometimes you can have more
comprehensive integration tests when it
comes to unit tests we do have our own
developed script in our you know on push
events that we also tried to build the
software try to to run unit tests and
only and that's again on every code push
that we do because we don't want you to
figure that out later but that's an
internal process that just makes sense
to us every company would likely have
different processes no I'm just curious
because in terms of like the the reason
I was asking that was also in terms of
say like if you're writing a piece of
code which might not require say like an
infrastructure code analysis like you're
not pushing a terraform template it's
just like some Java quotative writing
then I guess could there be a case that
you only run the unit tests and the
static I mean the sonar Cube and SAS and
SCA that could be depending on the
implementation or does is that a choice
for the implementation or could there be
some intelligence built in based on what
you're pushing I mean at the end of the
day it can be anything that you
implement behind that service in a
pipelineless concept it in our case we
run them all and you select when you
want us to act even in a terraform we do
scan for infrastructure as code
vulnerabilities so we can find
vulnerabilities in the terraform but
when it starts with anything Dynamic
that's where you probably want to have
your pipeline anything that is static on
source code you can do with a
pipelineless approach with a caveat that
it needs to be timely okay so since you
brought up that since it's timely so how
do you measure that so for example just
at the top of my hand I remember that
GitHub has 30 or 40 minutes time that
you can actually update your check that
you're running so if you do like a check
on a PR for example that needs to be
finished within a very fairly short time
frame you can do things on push as well
but at the end of the day if it's a long
process you probably want to edit into a
pipeline anyways because you want to see
the logs you want to see everything that
is going on and that's script as opposed
to a pipelineless security approach
which is typically controlled from a
central console and then it is
essentially you think about the maybe on
if it's a security team the security
team controls the pipeline less approach
for the entire company right maybe to
devops team that just wants to see
governance maybe it's just a code
coverage scan or maybe uh linters or
make sure that you don't overwrite their
terraform scripts whatever it is in that
case they will control it centrally
right but that is something that
developers will not necessarily need to
look at the logs because if there's an
issue there that might be an issue with
the devops team or might be an issue
with security and that goes back to what
is the thing that you want to expose to
the developer that if it fails it will
the developer will be fine with that red
icon next to the developer versus what
do you want to provide privately
security you probably want to provided
privately first maybe quality in some
cases as well but that's kind of the
difference whether it's in the pipeline
versus on a separate pipeline that you
don't have much visibility into until
you get a private message or until you
it can also be a comment on a commit it
doesn't need to be only a message to the
developer right you can annotate in line
in the commit and gonna be okay with
that as well so it's really up to what
is the automation that you set up with
this the thing that you just talked
about delivering a message privately
through the developer not a shame also
brought me to this blog that I read on
your blog portal at arnica which talked
about something called as a result
sensitivity I'll also reference this on
our show notes for our listeners but we
talked about how actually telling
someone that you had a high security
risk in your code base could also be an
attack Vector for an Insider attack I
think that's what it is saying so can
you explain that a bit to our listeners
yes so thank think about it this way
let's say that you manage all of your
security vulnerabilities in jira as well
as you manage all of the rest of your
backlog now as an adversary or maybe
Insider threat to the company I am a
developer I can you know maybe I am
going to leave the company and now I see
all the issues with the target security
and I know that there is a SQL injection
and I know that this issue is in fact in
Maine in the main branch
right well I see where the problem is I
can see how the database is built and
then I can go and exploit it because I
know it's right there and it's not fixed
yet for that if you want to minimize
your risk not only in the product but
also the exposure of certain findings
that's how you probably want to handle
that you want to handle it either in a
private way or maybe allow and if you
can configure your issues or issue
tracking system in a in a very granular
way then just create issues in a
different project and let only the
owners of that product or maybe the the
principal developers whatever only then
to access that project but then okay
it's a separate project for security or
it's a separate project for security for
each other project that you have and
then okay how do you manage it so you
have a lot of questions that you need to
answer to make that separation and
therefore the way at least that we solve
that is that we track all the issues
automatically with then arnica and then
we have a like a slash command that you
can use in your maybe a teams or a slack
and you can ask hey which
vulnerabilities I introduced as a
developer and then you'll get a list of
all of the vulnerabilities that are
associated to you specifically to your
code attribution another way you can do
that is do something similar with the
slash command and ask hey what are the
vulnerabilities Associated to the
product owners of that product and me as
a product owner I will be able to see
only the issues associated to the
product that I'm accountable for so it
will also get to the point that one you
have private findings and two you really
get only the important things that the
governance team or the central team
decided to expose to you that's quite
interesting to note I never really
thought of the fact that the way we
manage vulnerabilities could also be an
attack Vector it is and by the way
another idea try to open it your ticket
with a finding that says you have a
hard-coded secret okay so where's the
secret here's the link
yeah don't get me started actually I
spent nearly two days trying to like
wipe out git history with a sad quota
secret it's not that easy it messes up
the whole branching and everything you
know so yeah it's not an easy task so
imagine pointing someone to that and
then trying to like delete the history
oh God yeah it's a mess funny point when
we run Secrets detection and mitigation
with our pipeline security approach so
we have a patented way to you know
mitigate that secret and we provide
three buttons to the developer we say
either fix it for me or I'll fix it
myself or dismiss maybe I don't know
it's a private key that only you use in
your uni test whatever right I can tell
you based on our analytics we did not
see any developer click on the I will
fix it myself button twice because
that's exactly what you were doing you
had to go through that history and
change that it's not easy really not
easy yeah it's very messy this actually
leads me to one of the questions that I
think I have seen a feature on on GitHub
right where they don't let you they also
have a kind of a pre-commit I guess it's
on the main branch but they don't let
you push if there's a hard-coded secret
so how would that be different from say
the pipelineless approach I think in
fact I remember there was this the very
interesting blog again on arnica which
said zero new hard-coded secrets so how
does that effort look compared to say
what this GitHub push committers I don't
know what it's called push pre-commit
I'm forgetting the name but there's some
way that you can avoid hard-coded
Secrets going into the code so first
Kudos you really did your homework I
mean apart from the homework there's
also been a lot of pain where I have
actually committed like I should be
mentioning in this on software
engineering radio but I have actually
committed secrets and I've tried like
wiping it out and yeah there's a lot of
pain involved with the question that I'm
asking so okay awesome so I'll tell you
the difference the way that GitHub
Advanced security does that is that they
have something that is called receive
hook that a pre-received hook is is a
known hook with a git specs essentially
and it means before the push of that
code is actually being stored persisted
they run certain checks and then if it
doesn't meet all of their checks then
they can tell you back hey you can't
push that code it's very similar to
access control check that you can have
that says hey you can't push it now okay
but then when you have it you get the
message back as a developer and it says
even with a custom message it will say
you need to fix it or this is the link
to the guide in the company that tells
you how to fix it and then you go
through the exact same process that you
just mentioned you need to go and remove
it from the history with arnica you
don't need to do it with our approach as
we see the code that is being pushed we
overwrite it for you and that's the main
difference because the developer
experience is essentially our mainstream
with Antarctica now I'm not saying that
GitHub doesn't have a great developer
experience as a customer phenomenal
developer experience but at the end of
the day with that particular feature you
want to make it least painful for the
developer especially in such a sensitive
issue because the moment of the secret
is in your repo anyone else that clones
that repo can get to that secret by just
iterating through the commits or do the
just go through the audit log of the
commits you'll be able to see that right
so that's why we do everything runtime
and just override it for the developer
and therefore you have that button that
I mentioned that says fix it for me
which it does exactly what it should do
it fixes it for the developer while
ensuring that no one else actually has a
copy of that secret on their laptops and
if they do we provide that insight as
well that's interesting and let me just
move on to some more questions I want to
talk a little bit about two areas one is
of course the false positives right so
all of these tools produce false
positives I'm assuming a pipelineless
approach will also have the same
problems or yes I wish I could say no of
course not but
so that's an honest answer yeah we have
zero false positives that's how you know
that we like okay okay but then does it
learn on the reason I asked that
question was also because you said that
things are customized to every developer
right so then how does your how does the
intelligence build because some of the
like the other tooling the the false
positives kind of kind of reduce because
you set up things as a profile and
that's applied across the entire project
can you do the same thing with the
pipeline list does it make sense so with
the pipeliness approach again it depends
what you implement you can have full
scans you can have partial scans and
such but at the end of the day you will
have false positives no matter what you
do that's the nature of handling or
finding security vulnerabilities in code
and at the end of the day if you provide
that feedback very quickly to the
developer and that's essentially what we
see even if it's a false positive it's
like okay fine I'm just gonna say
dismiss because it's not it's not
something that occurs that frequently
with small code changes and therefore
when you save the code you can say Ah
that's not a big deal I'll just dismiss
it and you know we're good or and that's
essentially the balance that you have
because if you provide all results every
time you will create a lot of fatigue if
you provide it in small chunks on
something that developers already have
context in and they are the authors of
that piece of code it's very easy for
the developer to say you know what it's
not a big deal well you know what it is
or maybe you know what I'll just I'll
ask to accept that risk and I'll send it
to security so it's very iterative
process as opposed to you know I just
pushed code now let me look at the
pipeline let's see that it's right there
let's see it's succeeded you don't need
to wait for all that just get it
immediately and respond the next
question I wanted to ask you was another
thing that a lot of security teams are
grapple with is we have this list of to
do items and this is big backlog and
then you have to go through that list
and fix it and then nobody likes you and
then developer teams don't like you you
feel bad about yourself because you're
always running around with the to-do
list and eventually everything is
forgotten even though it's in the
backlog yeah I will do it we'll do it
and I wanted to know if there is with
this pipeline less approach because
you're sort of looking at like smaller
chunks of code and the feedback is
immediate do you think that this to-do
list culture will go away actually I'm
thinking about you just gave me a an
idea that might be really good for a
pipeline lesson not security maybe
pipeline less productivity approach
which is when you look at the code
changes when you see that the developer
just authored a slash slash to do thing
go and create the jira ticket and that's
it and send the developer the link to
the jira ticket hey or maybe modify the
code and add this is the Geo ticket for
that thing and that's it okay the credit
you commit on the code that says this is
the Geo ticket for it you've been like
you also provided automatic fix for that
is that what you say oh wow yeah that
would really be great
no but jokes apart I just wonder that do
you think there would be uh the to-do
list culture would that sort of go away
if the feedback is more immediate or
it's provided in smaller chunks I do see
that that to-do list or creating even
Geo tickets for the new vulnerabilities
is something that some companies will
still need to do because of compliance
because from whatever regulation they
have they would likely just want to have
that tracked however I do see how that
number of to-do issues is being reduced
or automatically resolved when it comes
to real-time feedback to the developers
so think about maybe a developer at
least I'll tell you how we would do that
with arnica when we scan a new
vulnerability obviously it creates a new
finding in our system and we
differentiate between a finding and a
feature Branch versus the finding in
let's say an important branch and what
happens is that we're not scanning only
the that stuff which is the
vulnerability we'll also scan the good
stuff which is the fix of the
vulnerability so if we detect that
someone actually fixed the vulnerability
and maybe merged it into the relevant
Branch we ought to close the issue I
mean you already have that with certain
workflows but it's mainly manual right
when you create a feature Branch you can
say a created the feature Branch for
that jira issue right and then when you
merge it that issue is being closed but
while you write code it's not a new
feature that you developed it's part of
that feature that you are develop thing
that you introduced in your
vulnerability and therefore you can
create a jio ticket but it's way easier
just to resolve it in your feature
branch and that's that's the difference
that I see between you know managing the
issues that are more functional maybe
let's say non-security specific or maybe
product features as opposed to fixing
security vulnerabilities that can can
have its own Silo as we discussed you
know privately and such but you also
want to have that capability without
looking necessarily only at the merge of
the code or having an issue open you
just want to scan the code and determine
hey did that developer just fix it yes
or no and if it's a yes just close the
issue and continue with that without the
need to have a project manager that will
follow up with you every time on that
right no actually I think that's a
useful feature in fact I built something
similar I mean only the jira part of it
and a tool that I work in my company
where also I kind of when the the fixes
happened it automatically closes the
jira ticket and I think that's super
useful so that would be really good I
want to move on to another two questions
actually these are two things that came
out of a conference I attended yesterday
the b-sides Bangalore where I said so
one thing that came out of that was you
know we talked about developer fatigue
right so the third party libraries right
or that we are trying to upgrade usually
that's not something that's very simple
like if you look at the the OSS supply
chain attack Vector that's not very
simple somebody in the audience a person
was giving the talk they had asked the
question to the presenter if there was a
way that when you scan for the third
party libraries can you also say that
how exploitable it is from the code
you're using because if you're using a
library and not using a method that has
the exploit then maybe you're okay what
are your thoughts on that so we actually
did quite a lot of analysis on that if
you go and pass all of the almost 300
000 cves that exist out there and you
actually look for the function names
even the word function I mean hey really
do really come from intensive reading of
all of the functions that are there
directly from the description or maybe
even you know other resources that
explain it you will see them less than
1.5 percent of the cves even have a
function name to give you now take that
1.5 percent and consider or take into
account as well that not all of these
function names are within that package
some of them are within a sub package
that that package actually uses and they
just say that's a function name of a sub
package that is being fixed okay so even
that 1.5 percent is not all direct
function names that you have now why I'm
telling you this because I know that
there's a hype around exploit
reachability of that code right but it
is a hike and hype has a tip at the top
and it has a tip at the bottom and and
at some point it gets to that Plateau we
are at that tip where it's at the top in
my mind where the the question that you
ask is actually being asked by a few
others whether hey could you provide me
that reachability and the simple answer
is yeah it's a hype and it will likely
reduce some of the vulnerabilities but
you will get a ton of false negatives
and its question is do you want to focus
or do you want to miss that's the
balance that you need to make we have a
different approach to look at that that
can't expose yet that will not get you
to either 1.5 percent will not get you
there and will not get you to the place
where you don't have anything so we're
working on something in the middle that
will actually give you a bit more
context and confidence about that
particular package that is being used
we're not Reinventing the wheel it's
actually something that we're taking
from a well-known capability with a
specific language that came from like a
the world of performance and kind of
Shifting that into into a security the
concept that will give you very similar
answers after this interview I'll do my
passive Recon skills and try to think
about that okay and this is why I gave
you the hint because I I figured out
that you might want to look at that okay
okay the other question which I wanted
to ask you would also I listen to in
besides was we talked a lot about GitHub
repos and then there is a lot of attack
vectors from GitHub applications being
exploited in fact I think there's some
things even in your in arnica's blog
about this what do you think about this
attack Victor and are there special ways
to protect GitHub repos because you
talked a lot about misconfiguration when
we started the show so there are other
any tips or does your company provide
that kind of a startup sort of to-do
list sorry I should be using to do but
yeah template I mean yeah it's hard to
say whether it's going to be a to-do
list or not but at the end of the day
every developer has its own behavioral
pattern and some developers behave in a
very specific way maybe in the in their
git clones it can be that way so I know
that you might look at the world of
Problem by just maybe streaming your
logs into your sim and maybe just ask
the sin hey give me every developer that
cloned more than I don't know 30 of my
repos in the last two hours or within
two hours you can definitely get it and
you might end up with some good results
but then what happens with you know
maybe build agents they can also clone
50 of a repos in the same hour and then
you start introducing false positives
with automation I mean the lean solution
is you know go and send it to the Sim
and do some statistical analysis and you
can live with this with these false
positives another way to solve that is
through machine learning this is the way
that we're looking at that we're
actually building clusters of behaviors
for each for each identity and based on
that we can determine which behavior is
more anomalous to that developer it can
be the git loans it can be then even
your commits in the code because in our
case the way that we're thinking about
the world of problem is that of course
you can exfiltrate source code of course
it is a risk but in the grand scheme of
things we're looking at either inside a
threat or a count takeover right and if
it's an Insider threat it might be a
piece of code that you typically don't
write that seems maybe not belong to you
not belong to the repo something odd and
therefore this is that type of an attack
scenario or maybe it's just me can't
take over and someone just tries to
clone your repos or get your secrets
from the repos and such so there's these
type of areas that we're looking at with
machine learning I mean as I said some
of that you can Implement with a good
sock analyst others are way more
difficult to implement like coding
Styles and such okay that's good I have
last few questions I think it was in the
end of the interview or one of since we
talked about security misconfiguration
can you tell us a little bit about this
Pro project called git goat that Anika
has oh yes yeah what is it so when I
said that I like to develop code this is
actually what I wrote with my arnica hat
this project essentially helps you to
test various tools when you try to
protect your supply chain or software
supply chain so what git go does it's
essentially it can be a Docker container
or it can be a small script that you
just give it a personal access token to
GitHub and org that you just created can
be an empty org you can even create an
Enterprise trial and spin that up and
then what arnica does is first of all it
goes to it invites users to your org it
misconfigures multiple repos so some
repos will have code owners maybe
without enforcement some of them will
have excessive permission some of them
will have maybe stale repos so you'll
have different types of repos that might
be misconfigured and then what we do on
top of that is that we go to different
open source projects that we know that
are vulnerable like web goats we've
clone them but since we care a lot about
those commits of the code then we want
to associate a commit to someone that is
actually in the company a piece of code
that I'm really proud of is the piece of
code that actually goes and rewrites the
git history and recommits the code with
the individuals that are invited into
your org and therefore you may see an
open source project that the author is
not from the open source is from your
org and now you can work with that so
that's what it creates it takes not only
that the nice things that it does as
well is also it simulates different
behavior for each of those users so for
example some users could be just you
know right into future branches and then
they create a pull request which is
approved by someone else from the org
all of that process is also included
with the same script and obviously part
of the pull requests are not approved so
if you want to check different areas of
the misconfigured org you can do that
and needless to say it also has
hard-coded secrets in it so if you have
any secret detector you can scan that if
you have SAS they can scan that org with
a SAS or with any infrastructure with
code vulnerability scanners or software
composition analysis scanners
essentially you have enough options that
you can run scanners on.org and you'll
have a variety of results okay
interesting so I'll definitely put a
link in our show notes to that and then
yeah people can contact you the last
question I have for you because we have
actually talked a little bit about how
arnica works and we did I mean the
pipeline list implementation that you
have and you did say that it's sort of a
web hook right listen through your push
events I wanted to also ask you about
the question about the licensing how
does that work because do you use open
source tools for doing all of these
different parts of your your tool chain
how does that work for consumers to pay
for this yeah so the way that we built
the value proposition of Veronica is
through some bad experience that I had
in the past
the thing is that I've been a buyer of
fast SCA is you know API security and
such and based on that experience I
acquired quite a lot of dashboards and
dashboards they showed me the risks but
in many cases they did not actually in
all cases they did not interact with the
developers in the right way or did not
really help me to mitigate that risk or
those risks that I presented put aside
even prioritization and even finding the
right owners for each product
so the way that we built arnica is we
said you know what I'm not a big fan of
hiding risks behind a paywall so
therefore what we said anyone that
integrates with arnica as small and as
big as company as it might be they get
visibility for free unlimited time
unlimited users
so even if you have an org let's say a
GitHub org or Azure devops whatever org
with 5 000 developers it's free really
free we charge for automation we charge
for what we can fix so if you're up to
viewing dashboards and you're not
willing to take an action on it then you
probably will not necessarily renew with
arnica next year so I don't want you to
pay but if you are willing to take that
challenge to talk with developers to get
them to mitigate risk to see your Trend
going down in risks that's where we
Excel and that's how we charge with
different tiers within arnica okay and
needless to say all of that experience
even onboarding is completely
self-service so anyone can try it out
the only limitation that we have it's a
known limitation and we're designed it
this way is that for example if it's a
if it's a GitHub org you cannot install
it on a personal org you can install it
only on an org that you create and the
reason is because at this point we're
really focused on the organizations that
want to onboard into arnica and there is
some additional complexities that need
to be considered if you are looking into
personal repos not in the git repos and
such but other areas that are not
necessarily important for now okay good
to know but anyway this has been great
it's been a very engaging conversation
and I just have to ask you the very last
question before I let you go is what's
the best way that people can reach you
well give me a phone call um seriously
no I mean like like any of the social
media sites so we want no no I'm kidding
I'm kidding okay but more seriously I'm
on LinkedIn so I'm I'm trying to be as
much as responsive as I can or go to
arnica.io we have a chat there you can
interact within arnica's app or Within
arnica's website and I mean literally we
have almost an entire company listening
to new Communications coming through
that chat and the first person that is
available uh is responding to that I am
actively monitoring that channel even
actually I'm monitoring that channel
more than I'm monitoring my LinkedIn so
but try to do both connect with me I
hope that friendly enough to the people
that connect with me would be happy to
get any any feedback on one on the
episode on the website on the messaging
on the product
we're really thirsty and really obsessed
about feedback on our product that's
great I think it's been quite a learning
experience for us also to know about the
concept of pipeline lists so thank you
for that and this is Priyanka ragwan for
software engineering radio thanks for
listening
thanks for listening to SC radio an
educational program brought to you by
IEEE software magazine for more about
the podcast including other episodes
visit our website at sc-radio.net
to provide feedback you can comment on
each episode on the website or reach us
on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter or through
our slack Channel at SC radio dot
slack.com you can also email us at team
sc-radio.net
this and all other episodes of SC radio
is licensed under Creative Commons
license 2.5
thanks for listening